Tufts Preview, A Publication of the Tufts University Student Admissions Outreach Program UP201
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts Preview, A Publication of the Tufts University Student Admissions Outreach Program
1983 -- 1994
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Office of Admissions and Financial Aid
UP201
0.25 Linear Feet
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains Tufts Preview, originally titled Speaking of Tufts. It is a publication produced by the Undergraduate Admissions Office for prospective students.
Biographical / Historical
Financial Services (1852-present) was established in 1852, when the university was founded (Light on the Hill, 82). This office was originally called the Treasurer's Office and it was where students paid tuition bills (Light on the Hill, 358). It was originally located in Ballou Hall, also known as the main campus building prior to 1899 (Tufts College Catalogue 1894-1895, 63).
The bursar's office, which used to be located in Miner Hall, was considered part of financial services. The first Bursar was the Rev. William A. Smart in 1894. Eventually, the bursar's office was placed under the Registrar's office (Light on the Hill, 358).
During the 1980s, the office had a window operating out of Sweet Hall, 419 Boston Ave. Medford, MA (which later became the site of Dowling Hall in 2000), where students would pick up and sign for their financial aid loans. Students could also pick up second semester loans in Eaton Hall (Office of Financial Aid records, UA038). From 197X to 1980, The Office of Financial Aid was located in Ballou Hall. In the summer of 1980, the office was moved to 128 Professors Row, the old Fulton Hall. The office is currently located in Dowling Hall.
Occasionally, President John Albert Cousens would have student files from the bursar's office transferred to him if students were having trouble paying tuition and bills. So specific accounts would fall under his office.
Scholarships and other financial aids were overseen by the Scholarships and Aids committee, which was part of the Faculty of Arts and Sciences. Awards are made by the Board of Trustees on the recommendation of the faculty. Scholarship applications had to be originally filed with the bursar (Tufts College Catalogue 1900-1901, 145).
- Tufts Preview, A Publication of the Tufts University Student Admissions Outreach Program, 1983 -- 1994; UP201.001; 0.25 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains Tufts Preview, originally titled Speaking of Tufts. It is a publication produced by the Undergraduate Admissions Office for prospective students.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Speaking of Tufts, 1983; UP201.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Speaking of Tufts, 1984; UP201.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Speaking of Tufts, 1985; UP201.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Preview, 1988; UP201.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Preview, 1989; UP201.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Preview, 1990; UP201.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Preview, 1991; UP201.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Preview, 1992; UP201.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Preview, 1993; UP201.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Preview, 1994; UP201.001.001.00010 (Box 1)